=To Kill a Songbird=
(Adapted from Shen Xiaoguan's
Bird Kills Seven People)
=Episode 11=
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
(Gathering Auspiciousness With the Sun)
(Born as a sparrow,
to perish upon striking stone)
(Shi is the trial fate
never meant me to escape.)
(Yesterday you bound me
and made me miss the right moment.)
(I nearly died outside the city.)
(After we come down the mountain,)
(it is best that our paths
be kept separate.)
(From then on,
we owe each other nothing.)
I said long ago
that you would get me killed.
Luckily, this girl is quick-witted.
She grabbed the arrow by hand,
shedding most of its force.
She won't die.
Guess
who wants to kill you.
Zhai Lu.
Zhao Chengxi is not the culprit.
There's someone behind him.
This case
is far more complex than we thought.
She's about to wake up.
Come drink some water too.
Why run so fast?
(Gathering Auspiciousness With the Sun)
Miss.
Miss, you're finally awake.
How's Luofu Manor?
We arrived too late.
It all burned down.
People and belongings
are pretty much gone.
What about Lu Yanchong?
He's not hurt at all.
You were injured saving him.
He wandered off on his own.
He didn't even
come to see you or ask about you.
This bird is surprisingly smart.
When we returned,
it followed us back.
It's calm and didn't make a sound.
Ms. Li.
What happened after yesterday?
You were unconscious.
Magistrate ordered me to take you back
to the county magistrate office.
I heard Zhai Lu
went down the mountain
after the incident .
I originally thought
Zhai Lu only trusted false proof
while in office.
That Zhao Chengxi was the culprit,
and he was only negligent.
Thinking about it now,
there's another hidden truth
behind the murder and framing.
Zhai Lu.
Shen Xiu was just
a servant tending my birds.
So what if I killed him?
Since you're here,
don't expect to leave alive!
Zhai Lu knew the truth.
Chief.
I found it.
13 years ago, Zhai Lu was
the magistrate of Huachang County.
Get up.
He knew every case detail best.
He deliberately concealed it
and now silenced witnesses.
He's likely the mastermind.
We
have no evidence.
To know whether
Zhai Lu is behind everything
is simple.
County Magistrate Jiang.
Will you go somewhere with me?
Sure.
Wait.
What is this?
I saw it by the roadside
and bought it.
I once thought
you were a cold bystander,
complicit with this world.
But now I know
you're someone bold.
I respect
and
admire you.
If fate were kinder,
I wish you weren't so alone.
This incense
is called Yearning Bitterness.
It traps one in illusion,
showing their happiest moment.
The heart wanders freely,
leaving no strength to fight.
You just let the girl leave?
I think she's quite good.
Fierce and righteous.
What are you looking for?
You'll flip the bookshelf.
(Elder Baiyun Biography)
Elder Baiyun Biography?
When did you
get interested in cultivation?
You know Elder Baiyun?
Elder Baiyun is a true immortal.
You know him?
If
he made a judgment outright,
can it be changed?
Do you think
words spoken by a true immortal
can be changed?
I have to change my name.
Especially the character Yan.
I can't keep it.
Master Lu.
You're now a court official,
registered in official records.
As long as your head is still on,
you can't change your name.
Why are you glaring at me?
That girl saved you, yet you ignored her.
Now that she has left,
and you lash out at me.
What is wrong with you?
Why leave again without finishing?
Sir.
Why are you suddenly interested
in alchemy and mysticism?
Too many misfortune lately.
I'm trying to ward it off.
By the way, Sir,
how much do you know about Zhai Lu?
Luofu Manor's fire was strange.
The arrow that night was strange too.
I suspect Zhai Lu...
You don't need to say more about this.
Find Jiang Chun if you need anything.
Li Fuyuan.
I know you suffered injustice,
but you're not the only one.
You can't expect me
to focus only on your old case.
Do you understand?
I understand.
Sorry.
Is your injury alright?
I'm fine.
No vital damage was done.
Thank you for risking your life.
You're too polite.
You saved me before too.
You owe me nothing.
(You probably)
(never felt bone-deep hatred,)
(so you don't know why I risk my life)
(to fight for the truth.)
(I also have)
(bone-deep hatred.)
Your older brother
was also my enlightening teacher.
Kan is a trap.
What am I trapped in?
Gen is restraint.
What does it restraint?
My bond with her
or her life?
If I keep approaching her,
Kan is water and added sorrow.
I never
thought
I would fear ghostly beliefs
and hesitate to move forward.
Li Fuyuan.
You truly are my nemesis.
Ms. Li, are you alright?
I'm fine.
Someone is following us.
I know.
Ignore them.
Should we shake them off?
Go through the market.
Give me a few more.
Thanks.
(Xuezhao Residence)
The place you mentioned
is Xuezhao Residence?
Sir.
They went to Xuezhao Residence?
Yes.
(Li Fuyuan.)
(What exactly are you hiding?)
Let me see if it's really you.
Zhai Lu.
♪A thrush's song
pierced the endless night♪
♪Blood splattered on the bamboo cage,
reflecting the cool moonlight♪
♪Thirteen years of frost and snow
sealed the old study window♪
♪I twisted the needle,
prying open the past♪
♪A cold stone marrow presses
against my palm♪
♪My older brother lay buried afar♪
♪Flames licked across that place♪
♪A list of righteous hearts♪
♪Who laughed in the dark at the panic?♪
♪I'm the shadow caged within
as well as the flying light♪
♪Only when hatred burns out did we know
how scorching our obsessions were♪
♪You said you'd die if you hit a stone♪
♪Yet you crashed into my fate's web♪
♪Pear blossoms fell all over
the wound on your shoulder♪
♪The wind in the bamboo forest
dispersed the hexagrams♪
♪The thrush carried the past away♪
♪I stood
at the end of the fireworks and gaze♪
♪You lifted a lantern to illuminate♪
♪That page♪